Finding Aid for the Carol Plantamura Collection of Photographs, 1964-1986
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
Carol Plantamura Collection of Photographs, 1964-1986
Mus. Arc. 93
Plantamura, Carol
1 box (18 photographs)
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
Contains eighteen photographs of Carol Plantamura with musicians associated with her time in Buffalo, including John Bergamo, Karl Kraber, Gregory Ketchum, Robert Dick, Yvar Mikhashoff, Buell Neidlinger, David Fuller, and Jeremy Noble.
Administrative Information
Terms of Access
Materials can be examined by qualified researchers in the Music Library during hours of operation during which Music Librarians are present. In order to insure access, researchers are advised to contact the Music Library in advance of visits.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Carol Plantamura, 2015.
Accruals and Additions
No further accruals are expected to this collection.
Biographical Note
Carol Plantamura was born in Los Angeles 8 February 1941. She earned her undergaruate degree from Occidental College and a master's degree from University at Buffalo. She moved to Buffalo in 1964 to join the first class of Creative Associates in the Center of the Creative and Performing Arts. She moved to Rome, Italy in 1966 where she was a member of Musica Elettronica Viva, an electronic music and improvisational ensemble. In 1971 Plantamura was a founding member of the Five Centuries Ensemble, along with John Patrick Thomas, Marijke Verberne, and William Christie. The ensemble toured widley and made six recordings of 17th century music for the Fonit Cetra/Italia recording label.
Plantamura joined the music faculty at the University of California, San Diego in 1978, and is currently an emeritus faculty member. She is also the author of a children's book, Woman Composer, as well as The Opera Lover's Guide to Europe.
Scope and Content Note
Contains eighteen photographs of Carol Plantamura with musicians associated with her time in Buffalo, including John Bergamo, Karl Kraber, Gregory Ketchum, Robert Dick, Yvar Mikhashoff, Buell Neidlinger, David Fuller, and Jeremy Noble.
Arrangement
The collection is chiefly arranged in chronological order.
Container List
- Double bass player Buell Neidlinger, October 1964, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item 1)
- Double bass player Buell Neidlinger in rehearsal, May 1965, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item 2)
- Percussionist John Bergamo, May 1965, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item 3)
- Carol Plantamura with fellow members of the Ars Nova Consort, Karl Kraber, John Bergamo, and Buell Neidlinger, rehearsing in the auditorium of the downtown Buffalo and Erie County Public Library spring 1965, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item 4)
- Carol Plantamura, John Bergamo, Nuell Neidlinger, and Elizabeth Crumb, in the Buffalo apartment of George Crumb, with score of his Madrigal I on the table, 1965, 1 color photograph; Photographer: George Crumb (Box 1, Item 5)
- Carol Plantamura, John Bergamo, and Nuell Neidlinger rehearsing George Crumb's Madrigal I in the auditorium of the downtown Buffalo and Erie County Public Library, spring 1965, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item 6)
- Carol Plantamura rehearsing with Buell Niedlinger, May 1965, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item 7)
- Carol Plantamura rehearsing with Buell Niedlinger, May 1965, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item 8)
- Carol Plantamura rehearsing with John Bergamo, May 1965, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item 9)
- Double bass player Buell Neidling on a snow-covered street in Buffalo, April 1965, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item 10)
- Carol Plantamura and John Bergamo, spring 1965, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item 11)
- Percussionist John Bergamo on a snow-covered street in Buffalo, April 1965, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item 12)
- Carol Plantamura in performance with David Fuller in old Baird (now Allen) Hall at the University at Buffalo, 1978, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item 13)
- Carol Plantamura performing with flutist Robert Dick and percussionist Gregory Ketchum, 1978, 1 color photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item 14)
- Carol Plantamura performing with flutist Robert Dick and percussionist Gregory Ketchum, 1978, 1 color photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item 15)
- Carol Plantamura after a performance in Buffalo, 1978, 1 color photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item 16)
- Carol Plantamura with unidentified female after a performance in Buffalo, 1978, 1 color photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item 17)
- Carol Plantamura with pianist Yvar Mikhashoff and musicologist Jeremy Noble in the Buffalo apartment of Sheldon Berlow, 1986, 1 color photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item 18)
Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog.
Subjects
Musicians--New York (State)--Buffalo--Photographs; Sopranos (Singers)--New York (State)--Buffalo--Photographs; Musicians--Photographs; Plantamura, Carol--Photographs
Genres
Photographs